[Music]
an invisible or concealed zipper can
really give your garment or project a
professional Edge and it's easier to sew
than you might think hi I'm Angela wolf
let me show you my foolproof way to sew
an invisible zipper you will need an
invisible zipper 2 in longer than the
zipper opening two pieces of fusible
interfacing and two pieces of fabric
first stabilize the seam where the
zipper is going to be inserted my
fusible interfacing is cut about an inch
longer than the zipper opening and is
wide enough to cover the seam allowance
and another half of an inch I'm trimming
one side of the interfacing with pinking
shears to prevent it from showing
through on the right side this is a
great tip if you're using lighter weight
Fabrics line up the interfacing along
the top and side raw edges and press by
holding the iron for about 3 to 5
Seconds lifting and
pressing next prepare the Zipper by
pressing the zipper teeth away from the
zipper tape make sure your iron is at a
low setting you don't want to melt the
zipper and just quickly press see how
this fold opens this makes it so much
easier to sew now take a look at this
handy line here on the zipper tape this
will be a good guide for you to follow
with the needle when it comes to sewing
here are both pieces of fabric and my
zipper start with the zipper closed this
will hopefully stop you from sewing it
in backwards flip the zipper with the
right side facing the right side of the
fabric insert one pin to keep the zipper
lined up and now unzip the zipper all
the
way line up the zipper tape inside the
edge of the seam allowance you want
these zipper teeth to land right here on
the seam so if your pattern calls for
halfin seam allowances you would line up
your zipper right here this is an
invisible zipper foot which makes it
really simple to sew see these grooves
underneath the foot they line up with
the zipper teeth and glide right along
that edge as your needle goes through
the hole
but you can also use a standard zipper
foot the difference is the foot will
Glide along the edge of the zipper teeth
like this line up the standard zipper
foot with the needle right next to the
zipper teeth using that handy line as
your guide and
Stitch this snip represents the bottom
of my zipper opening back stitch and one
side is finished zip up your zipper and
find that
snip now with a fabric marker make a
mark across from the the last
Stitch this will show you where to end
your stitches well done take a bow or
take a break and then start on the other
side turn the edge of the second piece
of fabric right side toward the right
side of the zipper pin it in place and
open the zipper all the way past the
last Stitch flip the
fabric remove that pin and start pinning
the tape in place just like we did
before pushing the finished side of the
zipper out of of the way you're now
going to stitch down this side change
the zipper foot to the other
side line up the needle right next to
the zipper teeth and Stitch when you get
to the mark representing the last Stitch
back stitch and you're almost
finished it's very important that the
last stitches on each side of the zipper
tape are even right here if they're not
go back and Stitch a few more stitches
on the shorter side to even them out
you're nearly there the final step is to
close the rest of the seam place a pin
along the seam allowance underneath the
zipper tape push the zipper tape out of
the way as much as possible and add
another pin back at the sewing machine
line up your needle here starting a quar
of an inch above the last Stitch just on
the inside of the Stitch line push the
zipper tape out of the way back stitch
once or twice and
[Music]
Stitch switch to a standard presser foot
and starting on that last Stitch sew the
rest of your seam closed so let's take a
look at our finished
zipper see how neat the seam below looks
and on the right side you can hardly see
the zipper teeth which is perfect since
it's an invisible zipper that's how easy
it is to insert one thanks for watching
get expert sewing instruction free
resources and supplies for your next
project by clicking the i in the top
right corner of this
video
[Music]